<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://markgreenway.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://markgreenway.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-02T16:17:16+00:00</updated><id>https://markgreenway.net/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mark Greenway</title><entry><title type="html">LIG Marine Blog: The Cost of Rushing: How One Small Oversight Led to Serious Injury</title><link href="https://markgreenway.net/blog/2025/lig-marine-blog-the-cost-of-rushing-how-one-small-oversight-led-to-serious-injury/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LIG Marine Blog: The Cost of Rushing: How One Small Oversight Led to Serious Injury"/><published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markgreenway.net/blog/2025/lig-marine-blog--the-cost-of-rushing-how-one-small-oversight-led-to-serious-injury</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markgreenway.net/blog/2025/lig-marine-blog-the-cost-of-rushing-how-one-small-oversight-led-to-serious-injury/"><![CDATA[<p>News &amp; Views on Commerical Marine &amp; Longshore InsuranceWorking quickly to get the vessel underway on schedule, the crew prematurely disconnected the gangway, removing the safety netting, and unintentionally leaving a dangerous gap between the accommodation ladder and the pier. When the pilot arrived, he found the gap too large to cross safely. Focused on final departure preparations, the crew did not respond to his communication attempts. Frustrated after several failed attempts, the pilot tried to climb onto the ladder himself but lost his footing and fell into the water, suffering broken ribs, a back injury, and deep bruises. Fortunately, his life jacket kept him afloat until emergency responders arrived. However, the incident delayed the vessel’s departure by 48 hours and left the pilot unable to work for months. Had the pilot hit his head or been crushed between the ship and the pier, this could have been a fatal accident.This situation highlights the critical need for comprehensive marine insurance. Whether it’s Longshore coverage for injured workers, Maritime Employers’ Liability (MEL) for crew exposure, or Protection &amp; Indemnity (P&amp;I) for liability risks, the right insurance ensures that businesses are protected from financial fallout when accidents occur. A single injury like this can lead to costly medical expenses, lost wages, and legal claims — expenses that could cripple an uninsured operation.Investing in proper risk management and insurance coverage isn’t just about compliance; it’s about safeguarding your business, your crew, and everyone who steps aboard.Mark GreenwayEnter your email address:Delivered by FeedBurner</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the rush to get a vessel underway, small details can have major consequences. A recent incident involving a bulk carrier and a pilot atte...]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://markgreenway.net/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://markgreenway.net/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markgreenway.net/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[<h3>External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</h3> <p>If you prefer publishing blog posts on medium.com or other external sources, starting version v0.5.0, <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">al-folio</a> lets you to display your external posts in the blog feed of your website! 🎉🎉</p> <p>Configuring external sources of super simple. After upgrading to v0.5.0, just add the following section to your _config.yml:</p> <pre>external_sources:<br />  - name: medium.com  # name of the source (arbitrary string)<br />    rss_url: <a href="https://medium.com/@al-folio/feed">https://medium.com/@&lt;your-medium-username&gt;/feed</a></pre> <p>The example above adds your medium.com blog post feed as an external source. But you can add arbitrary RSS feeds as sources.</p> <p>Any questions or suggestions? 👉 Start <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/discussions">a discussion on GitHub</a>!</p> <p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;postId=b60a1d241a0a" width="1" height="1" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>